<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Olanto Foundation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Olanto Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://example.org/foundation/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/foundation/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mail&#34;&gt;Mail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to contact Olanto please send an email to jacques@olanto.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;address&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Olanto Foundation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 Chemin de Champ-Claude&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1214 Vernier (Geneva)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swiss federal identification number: CH-660.1.763.012-1&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/foundation/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/foundation/foundation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Olanto is a not-for-profit Foundation managed under the Swiss law. Its headquarters are in Geneva, Switzerland but the Foundation is placed under the responsibility of the Swiss Confederation, to which it ultimately reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olanto is managed by a Foundation Board, which is helped by a Support Committee and a Committee of Experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olanto aims at creating and distributing free software in the field of Computer-Assisted Translation (CAT), Machine Translation (MT), multilingual search and other language-related fields. Olanto is an acronym which stands for &amp;ldquo;Open Language Tools&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-board&#34;&gt;Foundation Board&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-jacques-jpg-dr-jacques-guyot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/static/jacques.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; Dr. Jacques Guyot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacques is a senior computer scientist with over 20 years of experience in turning break-through technologies into professional solutions. He is also a researcher at the University of Geneva. He holds a PhD in Computer Sciences from the University of Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-karim-jpg-karim-benzineb&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/static/karim.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;  Karim Benzineb&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karim is a translator and a computational linguist. He has over 12 years of experience in designing and deploying CAT tools for Translation Services and LSPs. He holds translation and computational linguistics degrees as well as an MBA from the University of Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-alexandre-jpg-alexandre-poltorak&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/static/alexandre.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;      Alexandre Poltorak&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexandre is the founder of a company called Alsenet (link is external)and he is the vice-president of the Free IT Foundation (link is external) in Geneva. He is also Marketing Director of a US company called Elphel Inc. (link is external) which builds cameras and combines free software and open hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-gilles-jpg-prof-gilles-falquet&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/static/gilles.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;         Prof. Gilles Falquet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gilles is a professor and researcher at the Centre for Computer Sciences of the University of Geneva. His research is centered around the issue of &amp;ldquo;accessing knowledge&amp;rdquo; and its focus includes knowledge-based indexing and information retrieval. Gilles holds a PhD in computer science from the University of Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;olanto-consultants&#34;&gt;Olanto Consultants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-nizar-jpg-dr-nizar-ghoula&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/static/nizar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; Dr. Nizar Ghoula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nizar (Senior Java/GWT developer) holds a PhD in Information Systems from the University of Geneva (Switzerland). His fields of interest include the semantic web, knowledge representation, Information retrieval and ontology alignment. A very good Java/GWT developer, he is an active contributor to Olanto&amp;rsquo;s development effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>myCAT</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sofware/mycat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/sofware/mycat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;myCAT is a concordancer, i.e. a full-text search engine which, in addition to showing the relevant documents, also shows their translation (if they were previously translated) and automatically aligns the source and target language versions on the occurrences of the terms which is being searched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myCAT includes two modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Text Aligner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Quote Detector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Text Aligner displays and automatically aligns the source language and the target language versions of a given document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quote Detector compares a document to be translated with the complete corpus of previously-translated documents and detects all parts of sentences (or full sentences or paragraphs) which may be quoted from other documents. It then displays and aligns the source and target versions of that reference document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes myCAT unique is that its automatic alignment feature is based on alignment maps which are built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statmt.org/moses/&#34;&gt;Moses&lt;/a&gt;, a Statistical Machine Translation engine. myCAT can be used in any language combination; if no alignment map was built for a given language pair, a geometrical alignment algorithm will be used by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online demonstration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloads  (changelog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AGPL v3 sources @GitHub (link is external)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>myMT</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sofware/mymt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/sofware/mymt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;myMT is an automatic translation tool based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statmt.org/moses/&#34;&gt;Moses&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. the open-source statistical translation software. A demonstration version is available here (&lt;a href=&#34;http://srv2.olanto.org/WebTranslator/&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;) (the demonstration is based on The United Nations&amp;rsquo; Multilingual Parallel Text 2000-2009 , English/French).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myMT is composed of two parts: the translation servers (back-end) and the management server (front-end). The translation models are stored on the translation servers that are responsible for the translation. The management server is responsible for the division into sentences of texts to be translated and manages the translations depending on the languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myMT makes possible the construction of complex infrastructures that have numerous translation servers enabling the simultaneous translation of several sentences at once and the management of several language pairs. The specification of the configuration is done in one XML file. The start-up and the maintenance are automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myMT provides a graphical interface accessible with a browser that enables the user to select translation languages, to select (or download) the text to be translated. The outcome of the translation can be sent by e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myMT converts the documents into texts for the translation. It is also compatible with the translation of .docx documents while preserving the page layout. It is also possible to use it with .sdlxliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The translation server may also be used to build new translation models. myPREP can be used to create the training corpora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myMT is available both for Windows and for GNU/Linux (Ubuntu); please find the links to the respective installation files below. As for the sources, they are the same for both versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online demonstration (link is external)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloads  (changelog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AGPL v3 sources @GitHub (link is external)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>myPREP</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sofware/myprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/sofware/myprep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;myPREP is a text aligner software, a tool which makes possible to automatically align two by two the documents in a multilingual corpus. The outcome of the alignment is a translation memory in TMX format. The alignment is done at the sentence level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to myPREP, the production of training corpus for statistical translation is also possible (in Moses (link is external) format). Such corpora are divided into several parts for the training, the tuning and the evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myPREP also makes possible the alignment of comparable corpora. The outcome of the alignment is a set of pair of sentences associated with a score, the number of aligned terms, and the length of sentences. These functions can control the alignments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myPREP requires segmented documents corpora in UTF-8 format. The converter and the segmentation tool of the myCAT software are included in the installation of myPREP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;myPREP is available for both Windows and for GNU/Linux (Ubuntu 12.04); please find the links to the respective installation files below. As for the sources, they are the same for both versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloads  (changelog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AGPL v3 sources @GitHub (link is external)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
